MICHAEL NEUDER

(+44) 7470 675112 ♦ michael.neuder@gmail.com ♦ github

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a Computer Science and Mathematics undergraduate studying abroad at the University of Oxford until June 2018. I am fascinated by the use of machine learning, mathematical models, and computational science to predict and analyze the behavior of complex systems. I have a solid mathematical and computational background, as well as passion for learning and discovery that allows me to adapt quickly to a variety of research areas.

EDUCATION

University of Colorado, Boulder

Aug 2015-Present

B.A. in Computer Science

B.A. in Mathematics

Expected Graduation: May 2019

Overall GPA: 3.82 - Computer Science GPA: 3.97

University of Oxford, Oxford

Jan 2018-June 2018

Visiting scholar at Mansfield College Hilary and Trinity Terms of 2018

Coursework in Statistics, Graph Theory, and Numeric Analysis

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Laboratory for Atmospheric and Space Physics / Lockheed Martin Software Engineering Intern

Feb 2017 - Nov 2017 *Boulder, CO*

- · Joint program between the Laboratory of Atmospheric Space Physics and Lockheed Martin where University of Colorado students are trained in the skills necessary to start a career at Lockheed Martin.
- · Developed graphical applications using Python and C++ Qt Libraries.
- · Wrote interactive terminal applications using Perl and the Curses Module.
- · Developed graphical application testing suites using Eggplant Functional and SenseTalk.

Spire Manufacturing Solutions

May 2014 - Aug 2014

Manufacturing Intern

Colorado Springs, CO

- · Operated CNC lathes and mills to manufacture metal components.
- · Inspected parts to verify measurements matched specifications.
- · Repaired electric discharge machine and programmed machines to cut a custom part.

RESEACH EXPERIENCE

Lab of Dr. Elizabeth Bradley

March 2017 - Present Boulder, CO

Research Assistant

- · Used information theoretic measures to analyze the information produced by the climate system through water isotopic data in ice cores.
- · Wrote Python code to compute and visualize the isotope data and the information measures.
- · Performed multiple parameter sweeps of weighted permutation entropy to analyze the correlation between the climate's information production and the accumulation rate.
- · Used mutual information to explore correspondences between data sets from Greenland and Antarctica

March 2017 - Present Boulder. CO

Research Assistant

- · Developed neural networks using word processing and language analysis to predict reading behavior.
- · Synthesized data to train complex networks on a range of tasks.
- · Built classifiers and clustering analysis tools to train models on unlabeled data.
- · Created several convolutional neural networks to replicate the Structural Similarity (SSIM) score of sets of images in order to embody a more accurate image quality evaluation metric.
- · Created visualizations of network parameters and outputs using Python.

ACADEMIC CLUBS

CU Data Science Team

- · Participated in and earned credit for being part of the team.
- · Worked with a partner on an independent project with guidance from experts in the research areas.
- · Built machine learning models to explore a high dimensional embedding space.

PROJECTS

Image Quality Analysis
Numerical Experiments
Rubik's Cube Solver
Python vs C++
she
Connect Four
Hack CU 2017

Code written for machine learning and image analysis research.
A series of numerical analysis experiments written in Python.
Wrote a program in C++ that solves a cube from any scrambled position.
Created benchmark runtimes of programs in both languages.
Wrote a web application with Ruby on Rails to simulate a virtual girlfriend.
Created a graphical implementation of the game in PyQt.
Took part in hackathon and modeled the spread of infectious disease.

AWARDS

- Sewell Esteemed Scholars Award: Scholarship given by CU for academic excellence.
- Dean's List: Recognition given to CU Boulder students who complete a full time academic semester with a GPA of 3.75 or above.
- CU Honors Program: Lived in the Honors Residential Academic Program and participated in the Honors Community events.
- Visiting Scholar Award: Given to students who are selected from application pool to attend Oxford University as visiting scholars.

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Programming Languages (Experienced)Python, C++, PerlProgramming Languages (Proficient)Ruby, R, Javascript, Matlab, bash, CSS, HTMLLibrariesnumpy, scipy, matplotlib, tensorflow, scikit-learn, QtToolsgit VCS, LaTeX, Linux, Jupyter Notebooks

REFERENCES

Dr. Liz Bradley

- \cdot Professor, Dept. of Computer Science, University of Colorado, Boulder
- · External Professor, Sante Fe Institute
- \cdot lizb@colorado.edu

Dr. Mike Mozer

- \cdot Professor, Dept. of Computer Science, University of Colorado, Boulder
- · mozer@colorado.edu

Dr. Joshua Garland

- \cdot $Omidyar\ Fellow,$ Sante Fe
 Institute
- \cdot joshua@santefe.edu